<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://esportskingdom.nz/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://esportskingdom.nz/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-12-11T07:36:10+00:00</updated><id>https://esportskingdom.nz/</id><title type="html">Esports Kingdom</title><subtitle>Esports Kingdom contains articles, news, and views across multiple different esports games, focussed on weekly recaps and tournament previews/reviews.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Faker, Cloud9 and Overwatch come up big at The Game Awards 2017</title><link href="https://esportskingdom.nz/multiple-games/2017-12-game-awards.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Faker, Cloud9 and Overwatch come up big at The Game Awards 2017" /><published>2017-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://esportskingdom.nz/multiple-games/game-awards</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://esportskingdom.nz/multiple-games/2017-12-game-awards.html">&lt;p&gt;Esports took center stage during the fourth incarnation of Geoff Keighley's award ceremony. Three awards at the event were dedicated to esports; 'Best eSports Game', 'Best eSports Team' and 'Best eSports Player' as voted on by the fans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;media&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img alt=&quot;Screencap of the 'Best eSports Game' nominees from The Game Awards&quot; src=&quot;/assets/game-awards17-esportsgame.jpg&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;
		
		Screencap of the 'Best eSports Game' nominees from The Game Awards
		
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 'Best eSports Game' category saw last year's reigning champion and 'Game of the Year' Overwatch come up against four older games who are no stranger to the world of esports, including two properties from Valve. Blizzard seem to be on a roll with the launch of the Overwatch League on the horizon and no signs of the game slowing down, including constant balance patches and new characters such as Doomfist and Moria. It will be interesting to see if Overwatch can compete in this award again next year with the rise of esports-focused games such as PUBG bursting onto the scene, despite Blizzard's unwavering support of this game as a title and a esports scene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;media&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img alt=&quot;Screencap of the 'Best eSports Team' nominees from The Game Awards&quot; src=&quot;/assets/game-awards17-esportsteam.jpg&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;
		
		Screencap of the 'Best eSports Team' nominees from The Game Awards
		
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We saw yet another repeat performance in the 'Best eSports Team' category with Cloud9 topping the list. Cloud9 and SK Telecom T1 were the only teams to be nominated for this award in both 2016 and 2017, SK Telecom T1's nominations actually dated back to 2015. Cloud9 has become a recognizable brand in the esports world and that includes boasting rosters in; League of Legends, Counter-Strike, Overwatch, Hearthstone, Super Smash Bros., Rocket League, PUBG and Vain Glory. The brand also consists of dedicated and popular streamers such as 'Trending Gamer' award nominee shroud and many others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;media&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img alt=&quot;Screencap of the 'Best eSports Player' nominees from The Game Awards&quot; src=&quot;/assets/game-awards17-esportsplayer.jpg&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;
		
		Screencap of the 'Best eSports Player' nominees from The Game Awards
		
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After loses in 2016 and 2015, Lee &quot;Faker&quot; Sang-hyeok came back with a vengeance this year to sweep the 'Best eSports Player' category and take home the award statue. He wasn't able to attend due to being at All-Stars 2017, but was able to accept the award live on the stream from the American LCS studios. Faker hails from South Korea and represents the SK Telecom T1 team in League of Legends, leading them to victory in three separate $1,000,000 World Championship events (and runner-up at another). He plays the Mid Lane position and is generally perceived to be the best League of Legends player active in the scene, but now he has a trophy to prove not only that, but that he is the best esports player of the year.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Grady Hooker</name></author><category term="multiple-games" /><category term="features" /><category term="other-articles" /><category term="other-games" /><summary type="html">Esports took center stage during the fourth incarnation of Geoff Keighley's award ceremony. Three awards at the event were dedicated to esports; 'Best eSports Game', 'Best eSports Team' and 'Best eSports Player' as voted on by the fans.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://esportskingdom.nz/game-awards17" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Fast cars and racing pods! - Let’s Play Live GT Sport</title><link href="https://esportskingdom.nz/gt-sport/2017-12-lpl-gtsport-event.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fast cars and racing pods! - Let's Play Live GT Sport" /><published>2017-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://esportskingdom.nz/gt-sport/lpl-gtsport-event</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://esportskingdom.nz/gt-sport/2017-12-lpl-gtsport-event.html">&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Let's Play Live, Grady was able to attend the Gran Turismo Sport event at the SKYCITY Theatre. There was some awesome cars to look at and some great players and celebrities playing in racing pods to try and get the best times on the Bathurst track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;media&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img alt=&quot;Seven of top eight players competing in the grand finals&quot; src=&quot;https://scontent.fakl1-2.fna.fbcdn.net/v/t31.0-8/24799481_146508882665110_4554635008927445698_o.jpg?oh=d4642ebd09a6ebd421fda13ac98febd5&amp;oe=5AC8AEAF&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;
		
		Seven of top eight players competing in the grand finals
		
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before the event began the top competitors had to qualify to be on the stage, this was done in two parts. The first had people rock up to SKYCITY and play on the gaming rigs setup in the building in an attempt to get one of the top six lap times of the day and return for the main event. The was part was the online qualifier where players had to replicate the settings of the local qualifier to get one of the last two spots - both of the online qualifiers actually had the better lap times than the local guys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;media&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img alt=&quot;Four of the players in the opening exhibition match&quot; src=&quot;https://scontent.fakl1-2.fna.fbcdn.net/v/t31.0-8/24799373_146509002665098_8628166442644174865_o.jpg?oh=a4432126cc71922052a92eaa95606a3f&amp;oe=5AC6B692&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;
		
		Four of the players in the opening exhibition match
		
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main event, as with all LetsPlay.Live events, was broadcast live on SKY Sports 1 (a very prominent channel in New Zealand) to add pressure to the weight on the competitors shoulders. There was a warm-up exhibition race between some local Kiwi celebrities to get the crowd warmed up and ready to go for the big race and also set the lighthearted tone of the event. MVP has to go to Pua Magasiva (Actor - Shortland Street) who had everyone in stitches with his comedy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;media&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img alt=&quot;Gran Turismo NZ 2017 Champion Faine Kahia after the tournament&quot; src=&quot;https://scontent.fakl1-2.fna.fbcdn.net/v/t31.0-8/24831479_146508815998450_6011302397261229890_o.jpg?oh=e8ef196b0ae57c9f58faadac5f1540ff&amp;oe=5ACAA67B&quot;/&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;
		
		Gran Turismo NZ 2017 Champion Faine Kahia after the tournament
		
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the celebs had done their thing, it was time to move onto the big race of the evening. Eight racers, 25 laps around the Mount Panorama Circuit - top finish wins it all and take home the $5000 cash and a PlayStation 4. The event saw non-gamer Faine Kahia come out on top at the finish line, but Kahia was no stranger to the racing world. Kahia has been racing IRL for six years (he was the runner-up in the South East Asia Formula 4 Competition) and admittedly doesn't play videogames that often - something that didn't stop him from taking pole position in the digital world and netting a very real prize.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Grady Hooker</name></author><category term="gt-sport" /><category term="features" /><category term="from-the-event" /><category term="sports-games" /><summary type="html">Thanks to Let's Play Live, Grady was able to attend the Gran Turismo Sport event at the SKYCITY Theatre. There was some awesome cars to look at and some great players and celebrities playing in racing pods to try and get the best times on the Bathurst track.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://esportskingdom.nz/lpl-gtsport17" /></entry><entry><title type="html">DEVIL to Team LDLC and other changes (19 June - 25 June)</title><link href="https://esportskingdom.nz/counter-strike/2017-08-roster-changes-roundup.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DEVIL to Team LDLC and other changes (19 June - 25 June)" /><published>2017-08-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-08-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://esportskingdom.nz/counter-strike/roster-changes-roundup</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://esportskingdom.nz/counter-strike/2017-08-roster-changes-roundup.html">&lt;p&gt;There has been a lot of roster movement in professional Counter-Strike scene in the past ten days both worldwide and in the Oceania region with new teams being formed, old teams being dropped and players switching teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 class=&quot;logoheadline&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;logo-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://esportskingdom.nz/assets/logos/medium/grayhound.png&quot;/&gt; Grayhound Gaming sign the former Immunity team
&lt;/h1&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;Grayhound Gaming are a new organisation in Australia created in Match. With regards to the new organisation, team member Sean “Gratisfaction” Kaiwai spoke to HLTV.org:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;
	“Stepping forward towards the future, I can unequivocally say that we’re all extremely happy being able to call ‘Grayhound Gaming’ our new home. We’re certain Grayhound will carry forth a new standard for how every Australian organisation will operate and we’re proud to be a part of that.”
&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;The current  lineup is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;teamlist&quot;&gt;




	
		&lt;li class=&quot;player-name&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;flag&quot; src=&quot;https://esportskingdom.nz/assets/flags/AU.png&quot;/&gt; Callum 'BURNRUOk' Henderson&lt;/li&gt;
	
		&lt;li class=&quot;player-name&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;flag&quot; src=&quot;https://esportskingdom.nz/assets/flags/AU.png&quot;/&gt; Mohammed 'MoeycQ' Tizani&lt;/li&gt;
	
		&lt;li class=&quot;player-name&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;flag&quot; src=&quot;https://esportskingdom.nz/assets/flags/NZ.png&quot;/&gt; Sean 'Gratisfaction' Kaiwai&lt;/li&gt;
	
		&lt;li class=&quot;player-name&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;flag&quot; src=&quot;https://esportskingdom.nz/assets/flags/MN.png&quot;/&gt; Erka 'erkaSt' Gantulga&lt;/li&gt;
	
		&lt;li class=&quot;player-name&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;flag&quot; src=&quot;https://esportskingdom.nz/assets/flags/AU.png&quot;/&gt; Montheara 'prakM' Prak&lt;/li&gt;
	
		&lt;li class=&quot;player-name&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;flag&quot; src=&quot;https://esportskingdom.nz/assets/flags/AU.png&quot;/&gt; [Coach] Alex 'Magikkk' Langusch&lt;/li&gt;
	
&lt;/ul&gt; 

&lt;h1 class=&quot;logoheadline&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;logo-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://esportskingdom.nz/assets/logos/medium/ence.png&quot;/&gt; ENCE release their entire Counter-Strike squad
&lt;/h1&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;ENCE had already parted ways with their old team in 2016, but looked to make a fresh start with the SkitLite lineup in February of this year. The new team has failed to make any sort of impact with constantly bad results both online and offline – the only LAN event the squad attended was Lantrek 2017 and they came in 9th-12th after failing to make it out of the group stages. Management Assistant aNGeldusT had this to say:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;
	“After trying out numerous alternatives, the team and organisation felt that the situation wasn’t providing the right results and thus we decided to part ways. ENCE still strives for Professional eSports in the Nordics, and we will continue to spearhead that movement in the future. Rather than counting out CSGO, we are re-focusing our efforts to find the best match for our organization and a benchmark for Finnish CS, the way it’s meant to be.”
&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;h1 class=&quot;logoheadline&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;logo-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://esportskingdom.nz/assets/logos/medium/taintedminds.png&quot;/&gt; 'liazz' and 'dexter' step down from Tainted Minds
&lt;/h1&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;Tainted Minds are a Counter-Strike team that on paper looks good, but have not been performing at all online or in qualifiers and this has lead to them losing two of their players. Christopher ‘dexter’ Nong used a TwitLonger to explain that he is leaving the professional scene for now and “will be re-evaluating his options”, Jay ‘liazz’ Tregillgas has different plans and has been released from his contract to seek a new team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current  lineup is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;teamlist&quot;&gt;




	
		&lt;li class=&quot;player-name&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;flag&quot; src=&quot;https://esportskingdom.nz/assets/flags/AU.png&quot;/&gt; Connor 'chuch' Morgan&lt;/li&gt;
	
		&lt;li class=&quot;player-name&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;flag&quot; src=&quot;https://esportskingdom.nz/assets/flags/AU.png&quot;/&gt; Jesse 'InfrequeNt' Barker&lt;/li&gt;
	
		&lt;li class=&quot;player-name&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;flag&quot; src=&quot;https://esportskingdom.nz/assets/flags/NZ.png&quot;/&gt; Chris 'ofnu' Hanley&lt;/li&gt;
	
		&lt;li class=&quot;player-name&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;flag&quot; src=&quot;https://esportskingdom.nz/assets/flags/AU.png&quot;/&gt; [Coach] Fergus 'ferg' Stephenson&lt;/li&gt;
	
&lt;/ul&gt; 

&lt;h1 class=&quot;logoheadline&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;logo-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://esportskingdom.nz/assets/logos/medium/ldlc.png&quot;/&gt; 'DEVIL' has returned to the Team LDLC lineup
&lt;/h1&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;In the biggest roster news this week Team LDLC announced that they have resigned ‘DEVIL’ and that he will be replacing ‘mistou’, who will move to a substitute spot. Captain Kévin ‘Ex6TenZ‘ Droolans had this to say:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;
	“Our goals are very ambitious and recent results have sometimes been disappointing, although we have done great performances in EPL and haven’t been ridiculous at the Minor. But not to mention results, we felt we needed a change to allow us to go one step further. Mistou gave a lot to the team and he allowed us to move forward and we can thank him for that, but he missed a little something… I hope he finds it in the future! Now the road continues with Devil. It’s a player who showed a lot of strength, I hope we will do a good job together to allow him to explode. Here we go again!”
&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;The current  lineup is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;teamlist&quot;&gt;




	
		&lt;li class=&quot;player-name&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;flag&quot; src=&quot;https://esportskingdom.nz/assets/flags/BE.png&quot;/&gt; Kévin 'Ex6TenZ' Droolans&lt;/li&gt;
	
		&lt;li class=&quot;player-name&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;flag&quot; src=&quot;https://esportskingdom.nz/assets/flags/UK.png&quot;/&gt; Alex 'ALEX' McMeekin&lt;/li&gt;
	
		&lt;li class=&quot;player-name&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;flag&quot; src=&quot;https://esportskingdom.nz/assets/flags/BE.png&quot;/&gt; Antoine 'to1nou' Pirard&lt;/li&gt;
	
		&lt;li class=&quot;player-name&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;flag&quot; src=&quot;https://esportskingdom.nz/assets/flags/CH.png&quot;/&gt; Mathieu 'Maniac' Quiquerez&lt;/li&gt;
	
		&lt;li class=&quot;player-name&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;flag&quot; src=&quot;https://esportskingdom.nz/assets/flags/FR.png&quot;/&gt; Timothée 'DEVIL' Démolon&lt;/li&gt;
	
		&lt;li class=&quot;player-name&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;flag&quot; src=&quot;https://esportskingdom.nz/assets/flags/FR.png&quot;/&gt; [Coach] Julien 'Krav' Hernandez&lt;/li&gt;
	
&lt;/ul&gt; 

&lt;h1 class=&quot;logoheadline&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;logo-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://esportskingdom.nz/assets/logos/medium/kings.png&quot;/&gt; Kings Gaming Club forms new Australian team
&lt;/h1&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;Kings Gaming Club starts up with a bang grabbing up ex-Tainted Minds players ‘liazz’ and ‘wizard’, ex-Winterfox standout ’emagine’ and ex-Avant Garde players ‘Hatz’ and sico’. Team captain Travis ‘wizard’ Richardson spoke with HLTV.org about the move:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;
	“I’m excited to be joining forces with Kings Gaming Club and essentially building the brand from the ground up. We, the players share the same goals and aspirations and look forward to showcasing the prowess of this roster and representing the country overseas.”
&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;The current  lineup is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;teamlist&quot;&gt;




	
		&lt;li class=&quot;player-name&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;flag&quot; src=&quot;https://esportskingdom.nz/assets/flags/AU.png&quot;/&gt; Travis 'wizard' Richardson&lt;/li&gt;
	
		&lt;li class=&quot;player-name&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;flag&quot; src=&quot;https://esportskingdom.nz/assets/flags/AU.png&quot;/&gt; Chris 'emagine' Rowlands&lt;/li&gt;
	
		&lt;li class=&quot;player-name&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;flag&quot; src=&quot;https://esportskingdom.nz/assets/flags/AU.png&quot;/&gt; Jay 'liazz' Tregillgas&lt;/li&gt;
	
		&lt;li class=&quot;player-name&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;flag&quot; src=&quot;https://esportskingdom.nz/assets/flags/AU.png&quot;/&gt; Jordan 'Hatz' Bajic&lt;/li&gt;
	
		&lt;li class=&quot;player-name&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;flag&quot; src=&quot;https://esportskingdom.nz/assets/flags/NZ.png&quot;/&gt; Simon 'sico' Williams&lt;/li&gt;
	
&lt;/ul&gt; 

&lt;h1 class=&quot;logoheadline&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;logo-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://esportskingdom.nz/assets/logos/medium/prophecy.png&quot;/&gt; Prophecy signs five players to create new European team
&lt;/h1&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;Another new team on the scene this week as the British esports organization Prophecy sign five European players to make their first foray into the Counter-Strike scene. Max ‘quix’ Lindkvist gave a statement to HLTV.org about the new lineup:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;
	“We are excited over the new lineup and believe we can bring good results in the upcoming Gfinity Elite Series and in other future tournaments. We are thankful for the support and opportunity Prophecy are able to provide for us and are looking forward to getting a lot done.”
&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;The current  lineup is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;teamlist&quot;&gt;




	
		&lt;li class=&quot;player-name&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;flag&quot; src=&quot;https://esportskingdom.nz/assets/flags/NO.png&quot;/&gt; Karl-William 'kalle' Haraldsen&lt;/li&gt;
	
		&lt;li class=&quot;player-name&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;flag&quot; src=&quot;https://esportskingdom.nz/assets/flags/SE.png&quot;/&gt; Max 'quix' Lindkvist&lt;/li&gt;
	
		&lt;li class=&quot;player-name&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;flag&quot; src=&quot;https://esportskingdom.nz/assets/flags/SE.png&quot;/&gt; Fredrik 'slap' Junbrant&lt;/li&gt;
	
		&lt;li class=&quot;player-name&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;flag&quot; src=&quot;https://esportskingdom.nz/assets/flags/UA.png&quot;/&gt; Vladyslav 'arch' Svistov&lt;/li&gt;
	
		&lt;li class=&quot;player-name&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;flag&quot; src=&quot;https://esportskingdom.nz/assets/flags/HU.png&quot;/&gt; Ádám 'koloRRR' Domoszlay&lt;/li&gt;
	
&lt;/ul&gt; 

&lt;h1 class=&quot;logoheadline&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;logo-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://esportskingdom.nz/assets/logos/medium/rogue.png&quot;/&gt; 'powerputte' heading to Rogue Academy to replace 'KriLLe'
&lt;/h1&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;The last roster move this week was an obvious one, since ‘powerputte’ had already been playing a couple of matches with his new team, but still an exciting prospect for the team. Patrik “powerputte” Perjons released an official statement on Rogue’s FaceBook page about joining the team:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;
	“I’ve been practicing with the team for about 2 weeks now and we’re currently in Berlin at CaseKing for a 2 week boot camp ahead of the NeSA LAN in Finland and some Dreamhack qualifiers. So far I’ve been treated well and it feels really good in the team. Everyone are good friends so I think with good chemistry, good results will come after some time.”
&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;The current  lineup is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;teamlist&quot;&gt;




	
		&lt;li class=&quot;player-name&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;flag&quot; src=&quot;https://esportskingdom.nz/assets/flags/SE.png&quot;/&gt; Kalle 'perzon' Persson&lt;/li&gt;
	
		&lt;li class=&quot;player-name&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;flag&quot; src=&quot;https://esportskingdom.nz/assets/flags/SE.png&quot;/&gt; Kevin 'Kevve' Bohlin&lt;/li&gt;
	
		&lt;li class=&quot;player-name&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;flag&quot; src=&quot;https://esportskingdom.nz/assets/flags/SE.png&quot;/&gt; Jakob 'Barken' Bark&lt;/li&gt;
	
		&lt;li class=&quot;player-name&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;flag&quot; src=&quot;https://esportskingdom.nz/assets/flags/SE.png&quot;/&gt; Tobias 'shadow' Flodström&lt;/li&gt;
	
		&lt;li class=&quot;player-name&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;flag&quot; src=&quot;https://esportskingdom.nz/assets/flags/SE.png&quot;/&gt; Patrik 'powerputte' Perjons&lt;/li&gt;
	
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Grady Hooker</name></author><category term="counter-strike" /><category term="weekly" /><category term="roster-change" /><category term="fps-games" /><summary type="html">There has been a lot of roster movement in professional Counter-Strike scene in the past ten days both worldwide and in the Oceania region with new teams being formed, old teams being dropped and players switching teams.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://esportskingdom.nz/ldlc-devil-rosterchange" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Astralis kjaerbye: “One game at a time and just play our hearts out”</title><link href="https://esportskingdom.nz/counter-strike/2017-05-astralis-kjaerbye-interview.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Astralis kjaerbye: &quot;One game at a time and just play our hearts out&quot;" /><published>2017-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://esportskingdom.nz/counter-strike/astralis-kjaerbye-interview</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://esportskingdom.nz/counter-strike/2017-05-astralis-kjaerbye-interview.html">&lt;p&gt;Astralis may not have made it to the grand final of IEM Sydney, but they still put on a great showing making it to the semi-finals in the big stage. At the event Grady got to have a chat with star player kjaerbye about sightseeing in Australia and his preferred finals format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;media&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;iframe-cont&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img alt=&quot;Video of Interview with Astralis's kjaerbye at IEM Sydney&quot; src=&quot;https://img.youtube.com/vi/yO7tQkKZ3Q4/maxresdefault.jpg&quot;/&gt;
		&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/yO7tQkKZ3Q4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;
		
		Video of Interview with Astralis's kjaerbye at IEM Sydney
		
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;interview-question&quot;&gt;Grady: So, is it your first time in Australia?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;kjaerbye: Yeah it is our first time here, but it has been a pleasure so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;interview-question&quot;&gt;Was it a long flight to get over here?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a really long flight, it was about 24 hours in a plane. So obviously it was a really hard trip, but its been worth it so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;interview-question&quot;&gt;Do you take the location into account when you guys are accepting invites?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah. We take all the factors into consideration, but one of them is obviously the location. For example with this tournament we had two days off, which is perfect for a city like Sydney where you want to go and see things and want to experience the city. So yeah, we take it into consideration, but also a lot of other different things obviously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;interview-question&quot;&gt;Is there anything you have done while you've been in Sydney thats been really fun?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its been amazing because we went to the city and didn't know what to expect - it's a long way from home. But it reminds me a bit about The States, but the people are more like European so it is a good mix between things, it's really modern as well. So yeah, we just went to Sydney, went to see the Opera House which is drawn by a Danish architect (Jørn Utzon) as well, I believe - and then we went shopping and food and stuff like that. Yesterday we went to Taronga Zoo outside the city, which had this really good view of Sydney from a distance as well. We've got the most out of it I think, and now it's just all about the game and performing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;interview-question&quot;&gt;So do you find it easy when you are at a new location like this, being able to switch from &quot;Game Mode&quot; into &quot;Tourist Mode&quot;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, I think you get used to it. It's really important to experience things, that's something that we have agreed on together - we wanna look back on this, these trips, in 5-10 years and say &quot;This was a special part of our lives&quot; and when the family members ask you &quot;What did you do?&quot; we wanna say that we actually made something else than just playing there, because otherwise theres no value to the trip. I mean apart from the professional side, so it's really easy to switch on, from day to day. Obviously we are playing today so now it's just full focus on the game and that's why we are here mainly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;interview-question&quot;&gt;So, in the group stages that you guys have already played you had some of the local teams and you also had a Chinese team in there as well. Did you go in sort of expecting a different caliber from them? or do you treat them exactly like you treat any other team?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think there is a difference, we treat teams the same way...actually that's a bit wrong, we treat teams differently. A team we don't know such much about, we just play our own game, but sometimes we can look into our opponents we play a lot and the better teams and change small details and make tweaks. So, but I think we obviously don't expect the same, because the teams have different levels and stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;interview-question&quot;&gt;Do you find it easier to play teams that you have played many times over and over and know well or to jump into team that you have never played before?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, on one hand it is obviously easier when you know what the team is doing, but also by knowing none of the tactics they are running it's also easier because you can play your own game and it's maybe not as, as good team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;interview-question&quot;&gt;So you got FaZe coming up today is there anything that you think maybe they're going to bring to the table that's gonna surprise you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing that's gonna surprise us, maybe the veto process can surprise us in some way I can't explain right now obviously, but we played them the last two finals and we won one each, but we want our revenge from Kiev (SL i-League StarSeries Season 3 Finals) now. So yeah, we wanna go and play in front of the Australian crowd again tomorrow in the grand finals and that's our only focus right now is the semi-final. Take one map, one game at a time and just play our hearts out and that's why we travelled a long way to lift the trophy in the end&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;interview-question&quot;&gt;So obviously when playing the group stages, the semis and then the finals you got your best-of-ones, best-of-threes and your best-of-fives. Is there one that you guys sort of prefer? Is one too short? Or is five too long?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Five is too long in my opinion, tried it in Katowice (IEM Katowice 2017) against FaZe as well and it's just too exhausting for the body, too exhausting for the mind to play five maps straight and it's really stressful as a player and everyone was dealing with some serious headache and sickness, illness afterwards because your body is just so drained after a long game like that - it's a long fight against your opponent. I think best-of-three is perfect, for me. It's most of the time the deserved winner as well, so there is not really any excuses and the best-of-five is too long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;interview-question&quot;&gt;Well, thanks for taking time to talk to us here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Grady Hooker</name></author><category term="counter-strike" /><category term="features" /><category term="interviews" /><category term="fps-games" /><summary type="html">Astralis may not have made it to the grand final of IEM Sydney, but they still put on a great showing making it to the semi-finals in the big stage. At the event Grady got to have a chat with star player kjaerbye about sightseeing in Australia and his preferred finals format.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://esportskingdom.nz/astralis-kjaerbye-interview" /></entry><entry><title type="html">SK fer: “It is an incredible crowd and they love this game”</title><link href="https://esportskingdom.nz/counter-strike/2017-05-sk-fer-interview.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SK fer: &quot;It is an incredible crowd and they love this game&quot;" /><published>2017-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://esportskingdom.nz/counter-strike/sk-fer-interview</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://esportskingdom.nz/counter-strike/2017-05-sk-fer-interview.html">&lt;p&gt;After the grand finals at the Intel Extreme Masters Sydney tournament, Grady got to sit down with tournament winner fer to talk about SK Gaming's preparation coming into the tournament, hot off a win at cs_summit, and the best-of-five final against FaZe Clan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;media&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;iframe-cont&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img alt=&quot;Video of Interview with SK Gaming's fer at IEM Sydney&quot; src=&quot;https://img.youtube.com/vi/RpWnEBfo-lE/maxresdefault.jpg&quot;/&gt;
		&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/RpWnEBfo-lE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;
		
		Video of Interview with SK Gaming's fer at IEM Sydney
		
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;interview-question&quot;&gt;Grady: So, just first off congratulations - big win here. What was it like, playing in front of that crowd? Quite a loud crowd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;fer: To play with this crowd is always really good. The Australian crowd surprised me a lot, it's like an incredible crowd and they love this game. So we like to play with the crowd and also with the Brazilian support that was really good, even though they are a small crowd they make a lot of noise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;interview-question&quot;&gt;So obviously it was a best-of-five - could get really long if you went all five maps. Do you prefer the best-of-five or a best-of-three for a grand final?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[I] prefer the best-of-five because you can play different maps. Sometimes when it is only best-of-three you might not get really good maps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;interview-question&quot;&gt;If it had gone all five is the team communication still perfectly fine and calm when you are getting to that fifth map or is it starting to get ground down as you start getting a little tired?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, we are always very calm independant of the map we are always very very calm because any map you can, you know, you can lose, so you have to be calm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;interview-question&quot;&gt;So, before today how much practise did you guys put in specifically for just against FaZe? just for this grand final?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We trained a lot especially FalleN who is the captain. He tried to make a tactic game for [us] to play. So it took us a little bit of time to be ready for this game, but that's normal for every game that we play. So thats pretty much how it works and what we do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;interview-question&quot;&gt;Was there any point during it that you sort of doubted your team and thought maybe FaZe was gonna pull away with it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe a lot of my team no matter how many score they have. So I believe always, we can change the game and we can win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;interview-question&quot;&gt;What's next for SK? Obviously it looks like you guys, from Summit and this event here are starting to get back up to peak performance with felps now in the lineup. What's next? Are you guys upwards from here?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we are going home now and then after that there is the competition in Dallas (ESL Pro League Season 5 Finals). There is always something on, that's pretty much it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;interview-question&quot;&gt;So do you guys get much downtime between big tournaments or is it just straight to practising and straight back to work?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don't have many free time, now we going back home and after that we just gonna play online. There is not much time to rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;interview-question&quot;&gt;So, Australia, Sydney this tournament we just had may have been a new country. Is there any country that you haven't been to yet that you want a big tournament in?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to go to Greece. I think there is a competition going on there (ESG Tour Mykonos 2017), but it is in-between our holidays. So we probably wont play that one, but yeah, I would like to play in Greece.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;interview-question&quot;&gt;Thanks a lot man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Grady Hooker</name></author><category term="counter-strike" /><category term="features" /><category term="interviews" /><category term="fps-games" /><summary type="html">After the grand finals at the Intel Extreme Masters Sydney tournament, Grady got to sit down with tournament winner fer to talk about SK Gaming's preparation coming into the tournament, hot off a win at cs_summit, and the best-of-five final against FaZe Clan.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://esportskingdom.nz/sk-fer-interview" /></entry></feed>